Singer-songwriters write songs, but how do they do it?
创作型歌手写歌，但他们是怎样做到的呢？
Where do musicians get their inspiration from?
音乐家们的灵感从何而来？
What comes first – the music or the lyrics?
哪个先出现——是音乐还是歌词？
It turns out that everyone has their own way of writing which works for them.
事实证明，每个人都有自己行之有效的创作方式。
Bob Dylan is a musician with a unique musical style.
鲍勃·迪伦是一位有着独特音乐风格的音乐家。
It has been described as folk rock, gospel, country and jazz.
这种风格被描述为民谣摇滚、福音、乡村和爵士。
He told the BBC that he gets a lot of his writing inspiration from novels like Don Quixote and Robinson Crusoe.
他告诉BBC，他的许多创作灵感来自《堂吉诃德》和《鲁滨逊漂流记》这样的小说。
He said 'They give you a way of looking at life and understanding of human nature and a standard to measure things by.
他说："它们提供给你一种看待生活的方式，对人性的理解，以及衡量事物的标准。
I took that all with me when I started composing lyrics'.
当我开始创作歌词时，我把这些都考虑在内。"
It seems to have worked for him.
这似乎对他很管用。
He has had a career spanning six decades and has won many songwriting awards.
他的职业生涯跨越了六十年，赢得了许多歌曲创作奖项。
And what comes first, the music or the lyrics?
那么哪个先出现，是音乐还是歌词？
Stephen Sondheim, a musical theatre composer who died in 2021, said in an interview with The New Yorker that, when it comes to songwriting, the stress in a phrase is very important for him.
已于2021年去世的音乐剧作曲家斯蒂芬·桑德海姆在接受《纽约客》采访时表示，对于歌曲创作来说，短语中的重音对他来说非常重要。"
'You can start writing a lyric, and then the inflection of the lyric suggests a tune.' Therefore, in his way of writing, the music and lyrics come at roughly the same time.
你可以开始写一句歌词，然后歌词的语调变化会使人想到一段旋律。"因此，在他的创作方式中，音乐和歌词大致是同时出现的。
In 2022, Taylor Swift won a Songwriter-Artist of the Decade award.
2022年，泰勒·斯威夫特获得了"十年词曲创作人-艺术家奖"。
In her speech, she said lyrics are her favourite part of songwriting.
在她的获奖感言中，她说歌词是她歌曲创作中最喜欢的部分。
She describes the majority of her songs as having a 'modern storyline or references, with a poetic twist' and commonly uses real life experiences and conversations as influence.
她将自己的大部分歌曲描述为"夹杂诗意的现代故事情节或引用"，并且通常以现实生活经历和对话作为灵感来源。
Aside from lyrics, an important part of many songs is the instrumental backing.
除了歌词，许多歌曲的一个重要部分是器乐伴奏。
This is often created with chords, where at least three notes are played at the same time, often on a piano or guitar.
这通常由和弦构成，即至少三个音同时奏响，常在钢琴或吉他上演奏。
Chord progression is where different chords are played one after the other, and therefore can act as the base for vocals.
和弦进行是指不同的和弦依次奏响，因此可以作为人声的基础。
So, if you're feeling musical, lay down some chords, get inspired and give it a go yourself!
所以，如果你有音乐灵感，那就录制一些和弦，寻找灵感，亲自尝试一下吧！